We've seen two kinds of Python data types so far,
到目前为止 我们已经见过两种类型的 Python 数据
ints and floats and we've used
即整型和浮点型
arithmetic operators like addition and exponentiation to work with these values.
并且使用了加法和取幂等算术运算符来处理这些值
Another type is Bool which is used to represent the values true and false.
另一种类型是布尔型 表示值 true 和 false
Bool is an abbreviation of boolean.
bool 是 boolean 的缩写
Boolean Algebra is a branch of algebra dealing with
布尔代数是一种代数分支
variables whose values are true or false.
专门用于处理值为 true 或 false 的变量
Boolean algebra is named for its inventor George Bool.
布尔代数得名于发明者 George Bool
Boolean logic underpins all digital devices existing in almost every line of
布尔逻辑是所有数字设备的基础 几乎存在于每行计算机代码中
computer code and has transformed the way we live
并且改变了我们生活的方方面面
our lives which you can read more about in the instructor notes below.
你可以在下面的讲师注释中了解更多信息
We can assign boolean values like this.
我们可以像这样赋布尔值
It's not very useful on its own though.
但是本身并不太实用
We can use comparison operators like less than and
我们可以使用小于或大于等比较运算符
greater than to compare values and produce a boolean result.
来比较值并生成布尔型结果
Here, 42 is not greater than 43.
这里 42 不大于 43
So printing the result provides the boolean false.
因此输出结果后得出布尔值 false
Here, you can see a full list of the comparison operators in Python: less than,
这是 Python 中的比较运算符完整列表
greater than, less than or equal to,
小于 大于 小于或等于
greater than or equal to,
大于或等于
equal to, and not equal to.
等于 不等于
Notice that evaluating equality is performed with
注意 相等用两个等号表示
two equal signs and a not equal uses an exclamation point.
不等于用感叹号
This is a bit different than Excel or SQL.
这和 Excel 或 SQL 有所不同
In addition to comparison operators,
除了比较运算符之外
these logical operators are very useful when working with
在处理布尔值时 这些逻辑运算符非常有用
booleans and evaluates if both sides are
and 检查两侧是否都为 true
true or evaluates if at least one side is true and not inverse as a boolean type.
or 检查是否至少一侧为 true not 会颠倒布尔类型
Here's an example that evaluates whether age is within the range of a teenager.
这个示例会检查年龄是否在青少年年龄范围内
Here, you can imagine the 14 being placed in these two spots.
你可以想象下 将 14 放在这两个位置
Then, if both are true,
如果两侧都为 true
true will be assigned to the variable is_teen.
则为变量 is_teen 赋值 true
In other words if the person is older than 12 and younger than 20 this person is a teen.
换句话说 如果此人超过 12 岁 不到 20 岁 则是青少年
And here's not an action inversing the boolean type of same statement.
这是 not 运算 将同一语句的布尔类型颠倒了